# Thomas Tran

Experienced in senior management for multiple industries. Excellent people management and decision making skills. Expert Computer Knowledge, Experienced in Business Admin/Accounting

Woodbridge, ON tranthom618@gmail.com +1 613 600 9302

Studied at the University of Ottawa with specialization in computer sciences and business. Several years experience for the Federal Government managing a data entry team for high-security documents under Health Canada, handling medical studies and private sector pharmaceutical reports . Several years experience in the Toronto and Brantford area working in senior management roles for various industries from technology, marketing, and logistics. Co-founded a computer parts refurbishment company in Toronto prior to the pandemic, executive management role for client relations, employee coordination and sales support. Manager for a fire protection company with responsibilities for warehouse management, supplier liaison, client coordination, and service scheduling.

Willing to relocate to: Toronto, ON - Vaughan, ON - Mississauga, ON

# Work Experience

## **Warehouse Manager & Equipment Specialist**

Mainline Fire Protection Inc - Vaughan, ON August 2022 to Present

- · Re-organized and streamlined warehouse operations and inventory management.
- Inspected and serviced fire extinguishers of all types and brands.
- Coordinated pickup and delivery of fire extinguishers that failed inspections for the Dufferin-Peel Catholic District School Board and various commercial buildings such as offices and restaurants.
- Coordinated pickup and delivery of fire protection construction materials from suppliers to job sites.

## **Hooklift Truck Operator**

Jebsun Bin Rentals - Markham, ON October 2021 to June 2022

- Responsible for operating heavy machinery to deliver and pickup construction garbage bin rentals.
- Handled customer service at site locations.

#### **Customer Relations & Sales Director**

Office Tech Supply Toronto - Toronto, ON 2018 to 2021

- General management of a computer parts refurbishment company.
- Responsibilities included support and expertise of a 15-person team of hardware engineers, foreign import suppliers, accountants, salespersons, and customer service.

#### **Warehouse Manager**

Tellon Investment and Trade Inc. - Brantford, ON 2017 to 2018

- Oversaw warehouse organization and database management of wholesale garden products.
- Fulfilled large quantity orders for major retail clients ranging from Winners and Homesense.

## **Digitization Officer**

Health Canada - Ottawa, ON September 2015 to September 2017

- Marketed Health Products Directorate (MHP) responsible for evaluating the safety and efficiency of health products and procedures within Canada.
- Tasked with the digitization of the physical archives of the MHP Directorate
- · Coordinated data entry and meta-data organization within various database software.

## **General Labourer (Summer Student)**

Kelly Services (Ferrero Rocher, Aryzta, Nutrablend) - Brantford, ON 2013 to 2015

Kelly Services staffing agency for various factories in the Brantford area.

- While at Ferrero Rocher, worked two separate summers as a machine operator and another as maintenance and repair specialist. Gained significant experience in mechanical maintenance and repair for various assembly lines and robotics.
- Aryzta Bakeries, a major supplier of Tim Horton's baked goods. Tasked with supplementary supervisor role. Responsible for paperwork in regards to product serialization, inventory, quality control and manufacturing dates.
- Nutrablend, performed fast-paced heavy manual labour lifting 50+ lbs of products. Responsibilities included machine maintenance/repair as well as quality control.

#### **Waiter / Cashier**

Jumbo Dragon - Brantford, ON 2011 to 2013

Customer service, addressed customer concerns and inquiries

- Trained in safe food preparation and handling.
- Experienced with Point of Sale systems and handling cash, debit and credit card transactions.

# Education

#### **BSc in Computer Science**

University of Ottawa - Ottawa, ON 2013 to 2017

Assumption College School - Brantford, ON

#### Skills

- Food Handling
- · Retail Management
- Manufacturing
- Assembly
- Store Management Experience

- Computer skills (10+ years)
- Metadata
- Databases
- Data Warehouse
- Computer Networking
- Mechanical Knowledge
- User Experience (UX)

# Additional Information

- Experienced in computer software and hardware management
- Very proficient social and communication skills, excellent with people of all backgrounds.
- Flexible and adaptive; able and willing to learn new skills
- Punctual with an excellent attendance record
- Works efficiently with minimal supervision